Guide to the Keppele Hall Papers 1894-1980
Hall, Keppele Papers
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Keppele Hall Papers, 1894-1980
5607
Hall, Keppele
1 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Work measurement and job analysis studies.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Keppele Hall was an engineer, contractor, management theorist, superintendent of planning for Joseph & Feiss Company, and member of the National Board of Labor Managers. As a management consultant, he oversaw the implementation of management systems according to the principles enunciated by proponents of scientific management.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers consist primarily of fragmentary examples of work measurement and job analysis materials used in various manufacturing companies. The documents reflect Hall's effort to apply scientific management principles to practical activities.
Work measurement materials include tags, job instructions, data and miscellaneous notes and diagrams for the Tabor Mfg. Company (1912-1919), the Clinton Wire Cloth Company (1917), Lamson and Sessions Company (1926), and Strouse Brothers Inc. (1920); a contract for the Keppele Hall Contracting Company, Dayton, Ohio (1894-1913); and drafts and copies of the Articles of Federation of the National Industrial Federation of Clothing Manufacturers (1919). The papers also reflect Hall's association with Frederick Taylor's colleagues, Richard A. Feiss and Sanford E. Thompson.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Feiss, Richard A. (Richard Albert),1878-1954; Hall, Keppele,1872-1926.; Thompson, Sanford E. (Sanford Eleazer), 1867-1949
Subjects:
Scientific management.; Job analysis.; Management science.; Methods engineering.; Work measurement.; Business consultants.; Industrial engineers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Papers (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
CONTAINER LIST
- Biographical information on Keppele Hall by C.D. Wrege and J.C. Mundy, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Includes working paper entitled "Management Consulting 1913- 1926:The Keppele Hall Papers" by C.D. Wrege and J.C. Mundy, 1980, 31 pp.
- Correspondence. General., 1914-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Includes correspondence with Tracy Copp, Harold Marshall, Sidney Hillman. Includes notes on Mrs. Muskowitz.
- Correspondence., 1915-1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes Minutes of Baltimore Federation of Clothing Manufacturers note: This material is in order as taken out of one binder [folder 1 of 2]
- Correspondence., 1915-1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes Minutes of Baltimore Federation of Clothing Manufacturers note: This material is in order as taken out of one binder [folder 2 of 2]
- Terms in the Wire Cloth Industry by K. Hall, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  6 pp.
- Wage Systems by K. Hall, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  24 pp.
- The Standardization of Papers by K. Hall, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  5 pp.
- Reducing The Cost of Manufacture by K. Hall, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  16 pp.
- Preliminary Report on Overall Industry by K. Hall (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Planning Department as an Instrument of Executive Control by K. Hall, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  8 pp.
- Article of Federation. National Industrial Federation of Clothing Manufacturers, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Clinton Wire Cloth Company., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Time Cards, Work Reports
- Clinton Wire Cloth Company., 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Work Cards, Purchase Slips, etc.
- Clinton Wire Cloth Company and Easton Manufacturing Company, Taylor System Forms (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Contract (blank) to Keppele Hall Company, Dayton, Ohio., 1894-1913 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Eastern Manufacturing Company. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes Keppele Hall Report and paper specifications
- Eastern Manufacturing Company., 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Standing Orders.
- Job Tags. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lamson and Sessions Company., 1926 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Statistics and Data on Work Output and Report.
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 1 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 1 of 4]
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 2 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 2 of 4]
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 3 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 3 of 4]
- Strouse Brothers, Inc. [folder 4 of 4], 1920 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Forms-includes cost sheets, Diagrams, Instruction Sheets for work operations. [folder 4 of 4]
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Accounting System for the Newton Machine Tool Works by H.K. Hathaway (Box 1, Folder 19)
  97 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: The Balance Clerk n.n. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  66 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: The Follow Up System, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  21 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: The Planning Department by H.K. Hathaway, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  30 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: "Bonus Time Notes and Bonus Record Cards (Box 1, Folder 21)
  4 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Report to Plymouth Cordage Company, North Plymouth, Mass., on Form of Organization by H.K. Hathaway, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  28 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Report on Care and Maintenance of Belting (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Routine and Bonus for Time Clerk, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Order of Work Clerk, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Recording Clerk, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Storekeeper, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  62 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Standing Order for Balance of Stores Clerk, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  47 pp.
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Miscellaneous- Forms, publications (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Tabor Manufacturing Company Data: Miscellaneous- Forms, publications (Box 1, Folder 27)